A Guide to the Haight-Barlow Family Collection, 1791-1987
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Haight-Barlow Family Collection, 1791-1987
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 07-27
4.5 linear feet
The Haight-Barlow Collection consists of 4.5 linear feet spanning the years 1791-1987 and consists primarily of correspondence, financial and business records, deeds, newspapers, family histories, and photographs from the Haight and Barlow families, residents of Sully Plantation in Chantilly, Virginia from 1842-1873.
Vernon W. Barlow (1906-1986) and Martha S. Barlow (1908-1976)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Daguerreotypes require conservation and are restricted due to their extreme fragile condition.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Susan Barlow, July 2019.
Historical and Biographical Information
Industrious Quakers Jacob Haight (1782-1862) and Amy Clement (1787-1863) married in Dutchess County, New York in 1804. In 1842, Jacob Haight purchased Sully, a 700-acre farm in Fairfax County, Virginia, at a public sale for $12,145. The property included a house built in 1799 by Richard Bland Lee. The Haights and one of their children, Alexander Haight (1822-1880), relocated from New York and made their home at Sully.
Alexander Haight married his school sweetheart Phoebe Sweet (1824-1898) in 1845 and they built a new home known as “Little Sully” on the Sully property. In May 1845, Jacob Haight wrote to his daughter, Maria L. Barlow (1819-1903), in New York inviting her and her husband James P. Barlow (1813-1879) to come live at Sully with them. The couple eventually agreed and were living there by the time of the birth of their son, Jacob Haight Barlow (1846-1907) on September 3, 1846.
James P. Barlow took over management of Sully and the Haights deeded the house and a portion of the farm to him and Maria in 1855. In 1859, at age 13, the Barlows sent their son, Jacob Barlow, to Springdale Boarding School in Loudoun County. A few years later, the Civil War forced James Barlow, Alexander Haight, and Jacob Haight to flee, because as Quakers they did not take sides during the war, and the Confederacy accused them of being Union sympathizers. Both the Confederate and Union armies visited Sully during the war. By 1863, Maria Barlow, who was then living alone at Sully, fled to Alexandria and remained there with James until the war ended.
After the war, the Barlows moved back to Sully and their son, Jacob Barlow, became the farm’s manager. He married Henrietta “Nettie” Wilkins Shear Barnes (1844-1934) on September 13, 1870. Nettie had a daughter, Gertrude Barnes (1864-1920), from a previous marriage, and the three of them made their home at Sully. Two years later, they moved to Blue Rapids, Kansas where Jacob worked in a woolen mill and later became part-owner of a flour mill.
In 1870, Maria Barlow made an agreement to sell Sully to Stephen Shear and his son Conrad T. Shear after making a final payment in 1875. She and James moved to Blue Rapids, Kansas to join Jacob, Nettie, and Gertrude. However, Maria continued to make trips back to Virginia, and on one occasion Nettie accompanied her and gave birth to Carroll Jacob Barlow (1880-1956) on December 7, 1880.
James Barlow died in Blue Rapids in 1879, followed by his wife Maria in 1903. After Jacob Barlow died in 1907, Nettie moved to Manhattan, Kansas with her two children Gertrude and Carroll. She died in 1934. Gertrude married George Henry Failyer (1849-1945) and had three children. Carroll Jacob Barlow married Emma Westphal (1882-1966). They had five children, one of whom was Vernon W. Barlow (1906-1986).
Vernon W. Barlow inherited the Haight-Barlow family papers that are found within this collection. He and his wife, Martha Estelle Stevenson Barlow (1908-1976) made these documents and images available to Robert S. Gamble who used them for his 1973 book Sully: The Biography of a House, which is widely regarded as the definitive study on Sully Plantation. Gamble also had most of the papers in this collection microfilmed for posterity. The Haight-Barlow collection eventually passed down to Vernon and Martha’s son J. Steven Barlow (1939-2014). After his death, his wife, Susan Barlow, donated them to Fairfax County Public Library’s Virginia Room in July 2019.
Scope and Content
The Haight-Barlow Collection consists of 4.5 linear feet spanning the years 1791-1987 and consists primarily of correspondence, financial and business records, deeds, newspapers, family histories, and photographs from the Haight and Barlow families, residents of Sully Plantation in Chantilly, Virginia from 1842-1873. Subjects include family life prior, during and after living at Sully including later years in Blue Rapids, Kansas.
Series 1: Family Correspondence, 1816-1904, Boxes 1-3
This series contains correspondence between family members and friends of the Haight and Barlow families. The bulk of the letters were written while both families were living at Sully and document life on the farm, particularly during the Civil War period. Later letters in this collection date from after the Barlows had moved to Blue Rapids, Kansas. Also included are calling cards, a few surviving envelopes that housed the letters, photocopies of select letters made by Vernon and Martha Barlow, and a microfilm reel which features many of the letters found in this series. Of particular note is a letter from Frederick Douglass, the famous abolitionist, to “Miss Barnes”, likely Jacob H. Barlow’s future wife, Nettie W. Barlow. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 2: Personal Writings and Items, c. 1830s-1881, Boxes 3, 6, and 8
This series contains handwritten essays, report cards, an autograph book, a book, and a small pouch containing three rocks. Report cards and compositions are from Jacob H. Barlow’s time at the Springdale Boarding School in Loudoun County, Virginia. The autograph book was owned by Nettie W. Barlow and contains autographs from family members, friends, and other individuals from New York, Virginia, and Illinois. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 3: Deeds, 1838-1883, Box 4
This series contains deeds and agreements documenting various land transactions involving James and Maria Barlow. Most of the deeds involve Sully. Also included is the last will and testament of James P. Barlow. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 4: Financial Records, 1791-1934, Boxes 4 and 6
This series contains account and receipt books, receipts, blank checks, fire insurance policies, notes, and a business card. These records span from the Barlows time at Sully to their later years in Blue Rapids, Kansas. Many of the receipts are from Fairfax County and Alexandria businesses and individuals. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 5: Blue Rapids, Kansas Business Records, 1874-1891, Box 4
This series contains business papers from Jacob H. Barlow’s involvement in the mill industry in Blue Rapids, Kansas. When Barlow moved to Blue Rapids in the early 1870s, he formed a partnership named Cook, Chandler & Barlow, proprietors of Blue Rapids Woolen Mills. He later became a co-owner with Harland McGrew of the Blue Valley Custom Mills under the partnership Barlow & McGrew. In 1886, the two formed a partnership with M.L. Duncan and D.H. Miller which eventually became M.L. Duncan & Co., proprietors of Gem City Roller Mills wholesale dealers in flour, feed and grain. Documents included in this series are promissory notes, advertisements, accounting notes, receipts, deeds, agreements and a letter. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 6: Newspapers, 1864-1962, Box 5
This series contains newspapers and newspaper clippings from Alexandria, Virginia; Washington, D.C. and Kansas. Newspapers from the 1960s cover the opening of Dulles International Airport and its proximity to Sully Plantation. Also included is Maria L. Barlow’s obituary and a poem written by Nettie W. Barlow. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 7: Family History Papers, 1907-1974, Box 5
This series contains family histories, correspondence, notes, genealogical data, photographs, and bible records for the Haight, Barlow, Riley and Ten Eyck families. These papers were collected by Vernon and Martha Barlow. Martha Barlow was a descendant of the Riley family. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 8: Vernon & Martha Barlow Papers on Sully Plantation, 1938-1987, Box 5
Vernon and Martha Barlow took a personal interest in the history of Sully, the home of Vernon Barlow’s ancestors. This series contains correspondence, photographs, postcards, and notes maintained by the Barlows. Correspondence is primarily between author Robert S. Gamble concerning his 1973 book Sully: The Biography of a House; Fairfax County Park Authority Director James D. Bell; Robert E. Wagstaff; Louise M. Ryder; and Sully Foundation Ltd. There is also correspondence with Jacob H. Barlow’s stepdaughter, Gertrude B. Failyer, who lived briefly at Sully; and Sully’s last owner Lindsay Nolting. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 9: Photographs, c. 1850s - 1882, Boxes 5, 7, and 8
This series contains photographs, negatives, daguerreotypes, and a photo album depicting family members and friends of the Haight, Barlow, and Shear families. The twelve daguerreotypes are extremely fragile and faded. They are restricted to researchers at this time until they are properly conserved. Several of the daguerreotype images were reproduced as photographs and are accessible in this series. Nettie W. Barlow’s daughter from a previous marriage, Gertrude Barnes Failyer, was gifted a photo album in 1882. There are approximately 93 photographs in the album although many remain unidentified. Those that have been identified include Hon. Horace Greeley; Ralph Waldo Emerson; President James A. Garfield; Lucretia Garfield; Minnie Shear; Mrs. Pearce; J. Irving Pearce; Lillian Shear; Dan Hawkshurst; Frank Wall; George Nichols; Sadie McGrew Reed; Julia Craft Hewitt; Emma Hunt Means(?); Clara Holman; Will Julell(?); John Reed; Will Cook; D.W. Hindman(?); P. Wilton Smith; Ada Fitzgerald Nichols; Will Shear; Jud Shoecraft; Hiram Fowler; Blue Rapids Band; Mel Garwood; George Smith; Ada Nichols; Miss Olaf Krarer (Esquimaux Lady); Mrs. Cook; Mrs. Chandler; Katie Wilkins Ray; Marilla Wilkins Cary; Marshall Carry; Libby Cary; Will Shear; Etta Shear Barnes; M. Butler; Pheobe Shear Stewart; and Gertrude Shear.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
Index Terms
Barlow family; Barlow Martha S. (1908-1976); Barlow, Jacob H. (1846-1907); Barlow, James P. (1813-1879); Barlow, Maria L. (1819-1903); Barlow, Nettie W. (1844-1934); Barlow, Vernon W. (1906-1986); Blue Rapids (Kans.) - History; Chantilly (Va.) - History; Clement family; Gamble, Robert S. (1943-); Haight family; Historic buildings -- Virginia-- Fairfax County; Plantations -- Virginia -- Fairfax County; Riley family; Shear family; Sully Plantation (Fairfax County, Va.); Ten Eyck family; Wagstaff, Robert E. (1897-1970)
Container List
- Series 1: Family Correspondence, 1816-1904
  - Henry Clement to Sarah Clement [fragment], c. 1816 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Samuel Clement to Charles Clement, 1816? February 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Samuel Clement to "Brother", 1816 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Samuel Clement to Amy Haight, 1817 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Samuel Clement to Jacob Haight, 1817 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Samuel Clement to Amy Haight, 1821 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles Clement to Jacob Haight, 1824 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Samuel Clement to Jacob Haight, 1827 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Samuel Clement to Jacob Haight, 1828 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charles Clement to Jacob Haight, 1833 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Samuel Clement to Joanna Haight, 1821 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1839 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Isaac W. Thom to Maria L. Barlow, 1844 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alexander and Amy Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1844 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1844 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1844 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria and James P. Barlow, 1844 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mary and Deborah H. Stables to Amy Haight, 1845 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1845 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria and James P. Barlow, 1845 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1845 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Phebe and Alexander Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1845 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1845 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Amy Haight, 1845 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Amy Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1845 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Alexander Haight to James P. Barlow, 1845 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1845 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1845 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Maria L. Barlow to parents, brother and sister, 1846 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Phebe and Amy Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria and James P. Barlow, 1846 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - William Stables to Jacob Haight, 1846 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Phebe Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob and Amy Haight, 1846 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria and James P. Barlow, 1846 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Jacob Haight to Maria and James P. Barlow, 1846 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Phebe Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Maria L. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1846 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1846 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Hettie Barlow To Maria L. Barlow, 1847 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Alexander and Elizabeth Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1847 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Phineas Janney to John A. Washington, Mount Vernon, 1847 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Hettie Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1847 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Ann P. Merritt to Amy Haight, 1848 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - J.H. Stables to Amy Haight, 1849 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Ann P. Merritt to Amy Haight, 1849 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1850 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Amy Haight, 1851 or 1852 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - J.H.I. to "Friend", 1852 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Elizabeth Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1853 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Jamie Eail? To "Uncle", 1854 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Elizabeth Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1855 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Mary E. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1855 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Aaron Leggett to Jacob Haight, 1855 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Elizabeth Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1855 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Sam Morse to Dr. C. Haight and Amy Haight, 1855 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1855 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1856 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1856 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1857 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight, 1859 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Charles Clement to Amy Haight [2 copies], 1859 August 28, 1860 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Amy Haight to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1859 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Amy Haight, 1859 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to "Aunt", 1859 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1859 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Margaret A. Haight to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1859 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1859 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1860 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - John Hauxhurst to Mr. Barlow, 1860 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Amy Haight to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 February 29 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1860 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 June 14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Margaret A. Haight to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gennie Cleary to James P. Barlow, 1860 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James and Maria L. Barlow, 1860 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Amy Haight to Charles Clement, 1860 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Maria and James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Maria and James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 October 7 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 October 15 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James and Maria L. Barlow, 1860 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - E. Brown to James P. Barlow?, 1860 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1860 November 5 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Phebe Haight to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 November ? (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Gennie Cleary?, 1860 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1860 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1860 December 13 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1861 January 2 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1861 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to "Uncle", 1861 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1861 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1861 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - George A. Newbold to Talmidge Thom, 1861 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1861 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1861 December1 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - John Hauxhurst to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862? (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sue to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sue to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sue to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 February 28 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1862 April 20 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1862 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - J.H.W. Toohey? to Stephen, 1862 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Sgt. John C. Harmon to James P. Barlow, 1862 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Mrs. Denton (?) to Stephen, 1862 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Jacob M. Thom to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 August 28 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 August 30 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 September 5 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 September 6 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 September 9 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862 September 12 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - George A. Newbold to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - George A. Newbold to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1862 November 9 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1862 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 January 15 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 June 11 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 October 16 (Box 2, Folder 77)